Hi everyone, welcome back to our listening course.
In this lesson, we're going to learn about
two common question types, which are short answer
questions and sentence completion.
Our goal is to increase the percentage of
correct answers to 80%.
In this lesson, we are going to review
the format and key features of sentence completion
and short answer questions.
Understand and apply effective steps to answer sentence
completion and short answer questions by paraphrasing and
avoiding distractors.
And finally, practice answering sentence completion and short
answer questions in section 2 and section 3.
By the end of this lesson, you'll feel
more confident to tackle sentence completion and short
answer question exercises in the IELTS listening test.
So let's get started.
Sentence completion, or fill in the blanks to
complete the sentences, is a common question type
and frequently appears in section 2 and section
3.
For this type, they are given sentences with
blanks.
And your task is to listen carefully and
fill in the blanks with the correct words,
phrases or numbers.
The main purpose of this question type is
to check your vocabulary and assess your listening
comprehension.
Because it requires you to master paraphrasing skills,
use synonyms, identify main ideas and select information.
The given sentences are not 100% similar
to the sentences you hear in the recording.
Since the words are paraphrased, you need to
combine the skills above to handle this question
type well.
2.
Short answer questions.
This question type requires you to write the
correct answers within a word limit.
This is an example of a short answer question.
In terms of difficulty, short answer questions in
section 2 are more challenging than short answer
questions in section 3.
Why is that?
It is because in section 2, there is
only one speaker.
Therefore, the answers may appear before you hear
the key words in the questions.
That's why you shouldn't wait until you hear
Then, you just focus on listening for the answers.
Steps for short answer questions are similar to
those of form filling questions.
They are.
Step 1.
Read the requirement to identify the word limit.
Step 2.
Read questions and underline key words.
These key words can help you locate which
part speakers are talking about.
And, be more careful with all the information.
Moreover, you will catch the paraphrases of the
key words.
This is a skill that you always need
to improve.
Step 3.
Predict what type of information is missing from
each blank and distractors.
If you can't predict these distractors, it's normal
to get incorrect answers.
Step 4.
Listen and write the answers in the blanks.
Step 5.
Check the answers.
Students often skip this step.
That's why they often make unnecessary mistakes.
Sometimes, it just takes you 20 seconds to check
your answers.
By doing that, you can increase the number
of correct answers.